I couldn't say goodbye
Ienai ienai sayonara nante
even though I love you so much
Konna ni daisuki na no ni
You said we should break up
Mou wakareyou to
Kimi no koe ga kikoeta shunkan
and when I heard that
my world turned white in an instant
Mou masshiro ni natte
Karadajuu ni hashitta hibana
and sparks danced in my vision
Is forgetting you what I need
Kimi no koto wo wasureru koto ga
Mae ni susundeku koto na no?
to move on?
I could cry now, I don't understand
Wakaranai yo nakete kuru yo
Let's live in the moment, only in the moment
Seiippai meiippai ima wo ikiyou
We lived like that until now, too, I guess
Sou yatte ikite kita kedo
I couldn't say goodbye
Ienai ienai sayonara nante
Konna ni daisuki na no ni
even though I love you so much
（職員）早河のヤツ
さすがに終わりだと思ったのにな。
I really expected Hayakawa to be finished by now.
（職員）はじまりの樹の騒ぎが
静まったと思ったら→
We finally thought the ordeal with the Tree of Genesis had ended,
今度は　絶園の魔法使いだろ？
and now there's some mage of Exodus?
The fact is that he knows more about magic than anyone.
（職員）結局　魔法について
いちばん詳しいのは　あいつだ。
（職員）
国内だけじゃなく　国外からも→
His expertise is sought not only in Japan,
but internationally, as well.
相当
対応が迫られてるらしいからな。
（職員）まるで　絶園の魔法使いは→
It almost seems as if the sole purpose of the mage of Exodus was to reinstate Hayakawa.
早河を復帰させるために
現れたみたいだ。
The mage of Exodus's appearance was rather fortuitous.
（事務次官）絶園の魔法使いが
現れたのは幸いだったな。
Yes.
（早河）
はい。　あれの出現で　各国とも→
Because of it, other countries have begun to seriously investigate and research the Tree inde—
樹に対する　調査　研究を
本格化しはじめました。
I was referring to the fact that it was fortunate for you.
（事務次官）私が言ってるのは
お前にとってだ。→
Acting as a puppeteer again, what are you planning this time?
また黒幕気取りで　何を企む？
I merely wish to resolve the situation at hand.
（早河）ただの事態の収束ですよ。
むう…。
（早河）二つの樹には
文明の存亡がかかっています。
The very existence of civilization is being controlled by the two Trees.
それを収束できるのは
組織の中で　私しかいません。
Within our organization,
I alone have a chance of reaching any resolution.
And you will do this by any means necessary?
そのためには　手段を選ばんか？
はい。
Yes.
国連から　樹についての
説明を求められている。
The United Nations wishes an explanation regarding the Tree.
Be careful not to displease them.
機嫌を損ねんように頼む。
分かりました。
Understood.
Last year, an army dispatched by your orders was annihilated.
昨年　お前の指示で
対策軍が派遣され　壊滅した。→
You will still be held accountable for that.
その責任が消えたわけではないぞ。
（早河）ええ。　その責任は
左遷ぐらいでは取れません。→
Yes, and I cannot atone for it with a mere demotion.
私は　私の持つ情報を
すべて開示しますよ。
I plan to disclose all information that I possess.
内閣諜報捜査室なぞが
極秘裏に動かずともね。
Even if the Cabinet Intelligence Office secretly decides not to act.
You will meet an untimely end if you continue on this path.
このままでは　お前
ろくな死に方はせんぞ。
承知しています。
I am aware of that.
Episode 17
Marine Snow
（山本）あっ　ナッツ！→
Nuts!
They sell them in Singapore, too.
シンガポールにも売ってるわよ
ほら！
Look!
（夏村）バルセロナでも
買ってましたよね。
Didn't you also buy some in Barcelona?
Because of Hanemura, I've pretty much been able to fly around the world in two weeks.
（山本）羽村君のおかげで　２週間で
ほぼ世界一周できちゃった！
（夏村）彼は　大丈夫ですかね？
I wonder if he's all right.
Hanemura should eat nuts, too! Nuts!
（山本）羽村君も
ナッツ食べればいいのよ　ナッツ。
They're very nutritious.
栄養あるから。　ん？
ねえ。
はい？
Hey...
Yes?
（山本）
やっぱり　あれ　樹に見えるよね。
That does look like a tree, right?
（夏村）はあ。　人によっては
違う見方もあるようですが。
Yes.
Though people seem to have various interpretations of it.
樹が神のような存在として→
It's not unusual for civilizations to regard trees as gods.
認識されるのは珍しくない。→
ゲルマン神話のイグドラシル→
Yggdrasil in Germanic mythology,
and the Tree of Life in Christianity.
キリスト教の生命の樹。
Everyone seems to easily accept that Tree as another one of those.
皆　あれも　そんな樹の一種だって
あっさり受け入れてるけど→
Maybe we should think of it as something that only resembles a tree,
あれは　むしろ
樹に似た何かと捉えた方が→
while we search for the truth about it.
本質をつかめるかもしれない。
例えば？
For example?
Lately, among researchers and on the Internet,
最近　ネットや研究者の間では→
あれは　蛇か龍のようだという
意見が出ている。
it's being said that the Tree looks like a snake or a dragon.
蛇に龍…。
A snake or a dragon?
Yeah, and both the snake and dragon have been seen as gods at various times.
（山本）そう。　そして　蛇も龍も→
時に神とされる存在なのよね。
（滝川吉野）すごい。
あっという間に　ヒーローですね→
That's amazing.
Hanemura's become an instant hero.
羽村さん。
I'm starting to see what Samon and the others were planning.
（葉風）左門らの考えが
だいぶ読めてきたな。
ええ。　軍の攻撃を吸収し→
Yes.
The Tree of Genesis has the ability to absorb
生物を金属に変えることもできる
はじまりの樹。
the army's attacks, as well as to metallicize organisms.
Everyone's had to accept that.
皆　それを
受け入れるしかできなかった。
蓄積されていた不満。
Frustration was increasing.
それに応える超人的英雄の登場。
And then, a superhuman-like hero appears, addressing the problem.
はじまりの樹に
反感や疑問を持つ人が→
Anyone harboring doubt or animosity toward the Tree of Genesis
may now start revealing themselves to the public eye.
表立って
発言しはじめるかもしれない。
その勢いを　うまく利用できれば
ということだな。
And they're trying to see if they can take advantage of that.
（店員）お待たせしました。
Thank you for waiting.
（葉風）よし　食事に集中しよう。
All right, let's concentrate on our food.
Doing something while eating isn't good for digestion.
ながら食いは　消化に悪いぞ。
Right, let's concentrate on the meal instead.
そうですね。
よくかんで食べましょう。
Thank you for the meal.
（２人）いただきます。　ふふっ。
Oh, no!
（心の声）≪いかん！　昼間から
ふわとろのオムライスを→
We're eating rice omelet for lunch and smiling at each other across the table.
差し向かいで
笑いながら食べるなど→
We migh as well be on a date!
まるで　デートではないか！≫
I have to give up on Yoshino.
≪吉野のことは
諦めねばならんのだ≫
≪こんな　ひとときを
過ごしていては→
I cannot spend more time like this,
or I'll fall in love with Yoshino even more.
ますます
吉野を好きになってしまう≫
On the other hand, why hasn't Yoshino realized my feelings for him?
≪そもそも　吉野は　なぜ
私に好かれていると気付かん!?≫
≪富士で見せた
あの見事な推理力がありながら≫
He demonstrated such excellent deduction skills at Mt. Fuji.
If he has a girlfriend,
≪彼女がいるなら
女心にも敏感であろう！≫
he should be far more aware of a girl's emotions!
That's it!
≪そうか！
本気で好いた彼女がいるから→
He's in love with another girl,
so he doesn't see others in his field of vision.
ほかの娘など
眼中に入らんのか！≫
That's it, and that's how men should be.
≪そうだ　男たるもの
そうでなくてはならん≫
I could never accept anyone with a fickle heart.
≪浮ついた心根のヤツらは
こちらから願い下げだ≫
Oh, no!
≪しまった！　また　吉野の
よいところを見つけてしまった≫
I found yet another of Yoshino's admirable qualities.
At this rate, I will love him forever!
≪これでは　一層
好きになってしまうではないか≫
（葉風）≪どうすれば
吉野を諦められる？≫
What can I do to give up on Yoshino?
≪早く踏ん切りをつけねば…≫
I must hurry and decide...
≪心のどこかにある→
At this rate, if I keep wishing that Yoshino didn't have a girlfriend,
吉野に彼女がいなければと
願う気持ち≫
the Tree of Genesis will fulfill that wish and harm Yoshino's girlfriend.
≪これを　はじまりの樹が汲んで→
吉野の彼女を
害するかもしれんのだぞ≫
葉風さん　何にします？
そうだ！
Miss Hakaze, what would you like?
Oh, I see!
ソーダ　あったかなぁ？
（葉風）吉野！
Ice tea? Let's see...
Yoshino!
お前の彼女は　どんな娘だ？
はい？
What's your girlfriend like?
Pardon?
Just tell me!
いいから教えろ。
その娘は　私より容姿はいいか？
Is she better looking than I am?
私より性格はいいか？
Does she have a better personality than I do?
Is she smarter than I am?
私より頭はいいか？　どうだ!?
Well?
そっ　そんな　いきなり…。
What's with you all of a sudden?
なぜ気付かなかったのだ！
Why didn't I think of this before?
She is worthy of being Yoshino's girlfriend!
吉野ほどの男の彼女だ。
私より優れた娘に違いない！→
Of course she's more brilliant than I am!
その娘について　よく知れば
「とてもかなわぬ」で諦めがつこう。
The more I find out, the more I'll see
that I have no chance, and I'll finally be able to give up.
How about it?!
どうなのだ!?
ああ～…。
Ah...
Well?
さあ！
ふぅ…。
そうですね
彼女は　とても　きれいな子で…。
Well...
She is indeed a very pretty girl.
（回想）((で　これは手作り？))
So, is this homemade?
（愛花）((手作り風です))
((つまり？))
It's made to look homemade.
Meaning?
（愛花）((私は今日
「ゆせん」という言葉を→
Today was the first time I heard about double boilers.
初めて知りました))
((あははっ…))
((うん　まあ　市販品の方が
安心して食べられるしね))
Well, I guess I feel safer eating store-bought chocolates.
((それに　バレンタインデーに→
And besides, there's something special
about eating chocolates on Valentine's Day
彼女と
雪見ながら　チョコ食べるなんて→
結構　特別感あるよ))
with your girlfriend, while watching the snow fall.
((あっ！　ええ～…))
Considering how many other women gave you chocolate,
（愛花）((私以外の女子から
チョコもらっておいて→
彼女と特別もありませんよ))
I don't see how this is so special.
Th-That's...
((そっ　それは…))
（愛花）((怒ってませんよ。→
I'm not angry.
自分の彼が
チョコのひとつも　もらえない→
It'd be unfortunate if my boyfriend was so disliked,
嫌われ者というのも
困った話ですから))
that he couldn't get any chocolate from other girls.
Marine snow...
（愛花）((マリンスノー))
((えっ？))
It's a white snow, falling in the deep ocean.
（愛花）((深海に降る白い雪です。→
海があるかぎり
その中を永遠に降る雪。→
As long as there's an ocean, the snow keeps falling forever.
Because it's within water, it falls very slowly.
水の中だから
その降るさまは　ゆっくりで→
まるで　時間の流れが→
And it looks as though time is moving very peacefully, just in that spot.
そこだけ穏やかになっているように
見えるんです))
Doesn't it feel like that right now, as well?
((ここも　どこか
そんな感じがしませんか？))
((そうだね))
You're right.
((僕らも　深海艇で二人→
It's like we're deep in the ocean,
slowly being covered by marine snow.
マリンスノーに
降り込められているみたいだ))
（愛花）
((そのマリンスノーですが→
As far as what marine snow actually is,
正体は
主に　プランクトンの死骸が→
it's mostly leftover plankton breaking down into pieces.
粉々になったものだそうです))
((えっ？))
Huh?
So this snow may also be the remains of something unknown.
((この雪も　実は
何か得体の知れないものの死骸))
Actually, snow is just ice crystals...
((いや　雪は普通に　氷の結晶で…))
((そうであったとしても→
Even so,
there may be air pollutants such as exhaust fumes and factory smoke,
空気中で　排気ガスや
工場煤煙といった大気汚染物質→
昆虫の一部を
付着させている可能性は十分に…))
as well as bug particles on the snowflakes.
I'm really sorry.
((すみません。
やっぱり　チョコもらったこと→
You really are mad that I got chocolate after all, aren't you?
怒ってるんですね))
ふむ…。
Sounds like your girlfriend is very smart, with a broad imagination.
随分と知的で
想像力豊かな彼女なのだな。
No, she's just passive-aggressive and has a terrible personality.
いや　単に嫌味っぽくて
性格が悪いだけですよ。
Then this situation can't be good, can it?
だったら　まずいのではないか？
Going on a trip with me for weeks, I mean...
私と二人きりで
何週間も旅行など…。
If she's like that, then she must be furious by now.
嫌味っぽい　その彼女なら
怒り狂っているであろう？
Don't worry about it.
心配ないです。　あっ　ここだ。
Oh, here it is.
How can you be so sure?
なぜ　そう言い切れる？　何か？
What is it?
Are you saying I'm so unattractive
私は　男の食指が動かぬほどの
不美人だから→
that she has nothing to worry about?
その彼女は　余裕でいるとでも？
葉風さん？
Miss Hakaze?
Or are you trying to say that my personality is even worse than your girlfriend's?!
もしくは　その彼女より　私の方が
性格が悪いとでもいうのか？
No, you're quite beautiful.
いや　葉風さんは美人ですし…。
えっ？
And compared to my girlfriend, you don't have personality issues...
彼女に比べて
性格に問題があるわけでもなく…。
美人…。
Beautiful?
そういえば　夏休み中に　彼女と→
Now that I think about it, one summer vacation,
こんな話を
したことがあるんですが…。
we had the following conversation...
（愛花）
((クラスの子から　吉野さんを→
A girl from my class asked me to introduce you to her.
紹介してもらえないかと
言われました))
((へえ～))
（愛花）((なので→
So I made myself go pale and said that despite appearances
「あれは　害がなさそうで
実は　非道な人格破綻者だから→
you are quite cruel and full of personality problems.
紹介して何かあっても
責任が持てないけど」と→
I told her that if I introduced her, I couldn't be responsible for the results.
青い顔で言っておきましたよ))
((あっ…))
（愛花）((すると　なぜか
紹介してくれなくていいと→
And then, for some reason, she retracted her request.
辞退されましたが))
((あははっ…))
Since she has no chance at all, it doesn't hurt to squash her hopes early.
（愛花）((どうにかなる可能性は
ゼロですから→
早めに潰しても同じでしょう？))
((そうかな？))
You think so?
((意外と　うまくいってたかも))
It think it could have gone well.
If that were the case,
（愛花）((だとしたら
このかき氷機で削られるのが→
this ice shaver would be shaving you, rather than this ice, Yoshino.
氷でなく吉野さんになります))
((うっ！))
I'd freeze you in an industrial-strength freezer,
((業務用冷蔵庫で
固く固く凍らせて→
丁寧に丁寧に　削ってあげますね))
and then, ever so carefully, shave you down.
((わあ～
冗談に聞こえないなぁ…))
Somehow, that doesn't sound like a joke.
That's because I'm not joking!
((それは　冗談ではありませんから))
((あははっ…))
（愛花）((ほかの子に
目移りしてもかまいませんよ。→
It's fine for you to look at other girls,
as I must say that I'm curious about human shaved ice.
私も　人間かき氷に
興味がないでもありません。→
でも
そんなときは来ないでしょう))
But I'm sure the moment will never come.
（愛花）((私とつきあえるのは
吉野さんしかいないのと同じに→
Just as you're the only one who can date me,
吉野さんとつきあえるのも
私くらいしかいない。→
I am the only person who can date you.
少なくとも　私には
吉野さんしか考えられません))
If anything, you're the only one I could even consider.
Do you truly have the courage to betray those feelings?
((そういう私を裏切る度胸が
吉野さんにありますか？))
それくらいから→
After that, there wasn't much mention of other girls.
あんまり　ほかの子がどうしたとか
言わなくなったんです。
彼女には　やはり
僕しかいない気がするんです。
I can't help but feel that I'm the only one for her.
It isn't just about love or dislike.
好きとか嫌いとか
そういうのだけじゃなく→
彼女には　僕が必要なんだって→
I just know with certainty that she needs me.
確信できる気持ちといいますか…。
≪わ…　私だって　お前が必要だ≫
B-But I need you, too...
≪必要だぞ≫
I need you!
≪ああ～！　だから
この考えは　いかんのだ！≫
And this is exactly what I can't be thinking about!
（早河）羽村が
日本に帰って来ているそうだな。
I hear that Hanemura has returned to Japan.
Yeah, he's apparently suffering from jet lag.
（哲馬）ああ。
時差ボケに悩まされているらしい。
（早河）羽村のおかげで
世界中が　はじまりの樹について→
Thanks to Hanemura, the whole world is having second thoughts about the Tree of Genesis.
再考を始めている。→
All that's left is...
ならば　残るのは…。
絶園の樹。
The Tree of Exodus.
（早河）ああ。　そして→
Yes.
And the heart of the mage of Exodus.
絶園の魔法使いの心だ。
Shinjuku: Studio Alta
What is the Tree of Genesis?
A heated debate worldwide.
Because of the Tree of Genesis, the world is now at peace,
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]　はじまりの樹によって
世界は平和になり→
and the environment and public order have impro—
Rebuild Japan Party:
Leader Ogasawa Hisashi
自然環境も治安も見違えるほど…。
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]　絶園の魔法使いは
我らの救世主です！→
The mage of Exodus is our savior!
Japan in an uproar over
the mage of Exodus.
Full coverage of heated debate.
Shiba Chiharu, Attorney
我々は
はじまりの樹の存在を→
We had no choice
but to accept the Tree of Genesis's existence.
受け入れるしかなかった。
しかし！
However!
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]　はじまりの樹は
間違った支配者である！
The Tree of Genesis is a wrongful ruler!
What's going to happen?     Tree of Genesis vs. mage of Exodus
What?
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]　何を!?
絶園の魔法使いこそ…。
It's the mage of Exodus that...
（羽村）
ああ～　もう　こんな大ごとに…。
This has gotten totally out of hand...
（羽村）うわぁ～～！
（潤一郎）あっ　ここ痛かった？
Oh, did that hurt?
だいぶ
胃腸が弱ってるみたいだね。
Looks like your digestive system isn't doing too well.
（羽村）体全体がボロボロです！
You broke my whole body.
（不破真広）
吉野からの連絡を待ってんのか？
Are you still waiting to hear from Yoshino?
お前ら
吉野が絶園の魔法使いだって→
You guys think that Yoshino may be the mage of Exodus, don't you?
疑ってんだろ？
あっ。
Huh?!
えっ!?
絶園の魔法使いが僕のほかにも…。
There's another mage of Exodus besides m—
っていうか　お前じゃ
おかしいって言ってんだよ。
It'd be weirder if it was only you.
Your magic skills may have improved,
魔法の扱いは　うまくなっても
人を殺せる度胸は→
but you don't have a hint of the guts it takes to kill.
かけらもついてねぇ。
（羽村）うっ…。
So you knew all along...
（左門）やはり気付いていたか。→
我々は　こう考えている。→
Here is what we are thinking.
絶園の魔法使いは　心と体に
分かれているのではないかと。
The mage of Exodus may have been split,
separating the heart from the body.
（羽村）心と体？
Separating the heart and the body?
これまでの件を見ても→
The more we look back on events,
the more possible it becomes that Takigawa Yoshino is the mage of Exodus.
滝川吉野が
絶園の魔法使いだとの疑いは→
濃くなるばかり。→
絶対的な力を持つ
はじまりの樹に対抗すべく→
Before its fight with the Tree of Genesis,
絶園の樹は保険として→
the Tree of Exodus may have separated its mage's heart and body as insurance.
心を
体から切り離したのではないか。→
魔法は使えずとも　謀略を巡らす→
Though unable to use magic,
the bearer of the heart would have cunning worthy of Exodus.
絶園の心を持つ者。
And you're saying that's Yoshino?
それが吉野ってわけか。
臆測の域は出ないがな。
For now, it is mere speculation.
If Yoshino is indeed the mage of Exodus,
吉野君が
絶園の魔法使いだとしたなら→
その謀略は完璧すぎる。→
his subterfuge has worked all too well.
After all, having Hakaze fall in love with him would,
葉風ちゃんに
恋心を持たれるのは→
ある意味　はじまりの樹の加護を→
in a way, mean having the protection of the Tree of Genesis for himself.
自分のものにしたと
同じことだからね。
吉野を殺せるかと聞いたのは
その可能性も含めてか？
When you asked if I could kill Yoshino,
was that possibility a factor?
滝川吉野が絶園の魔法使いなら→
If Takigawa Yoshino is the mage of Exodus,
お前の妹を殺した可能性も
出てくる。
he might have killed your sister.
（潤一郎）必要とあらば→
If it comes to it,
吉野君を殺すのに手を貸すよ。
I can help kill Yoshino.
（羽村）うわぁ～～！
吉野の彼女の身柄を押さえよう。
Let's find the whereabouts of Yoshino's girlfriend.
（左門）彼女？
ああ。
Girlfriend?
Yeah.
Even now, Yoshino hasn't told anyone about his girlfriend.
いまだに　吉野は
彼女について誰にも教えていない。
理由は分からねぇが→
I'm not sure why,
あいつに　いちばん　影響を
与えられる人間ってことだろう。
but it means she'll probably have the most influence over him.
いい人質になる。
She'd be a good hostage.
ふん　さしあたり
滝川吉野をかばうには→
For the time being, it's a good way to protect Takigawa Yoshino.
妥当な提案か。
What?
なんだよ？
いや。
Nothing.
（潤一郎）
彼女が切り札になるかい？
Would she work as a trump card?
If Yoshino is the mage of Exodus,
吉野君が絶園の魔法使いなら→
大事の前に
彼女なんか見捨てるだろう？
he would probably abandon her if push came to shove.
If that's how it ends up, kill him.
そのときは殺せばいい。
A worthless mage like that would have no right to live.
そんな　くだらない魔法使いは
生かしとく価値もねぇ。
分かった。
All right.
じゃあ
吉野の彼女が誰か特定するか。
Then let's try to figure out who Yoshino's girlfriend is.
（左門）よかろう。
えっ？
Understood.
Now it can fly at any time.
これで　いつでも飛ばせますね。
Huh?
あっ…。　あっ　ああ～　そうだな。
O-Oh... Right.
うむ　うむ。
葉風さん？
Miss Hakaze?
（左門）
高校生にとっての彼女とは→
The girlfriend of a high school student
would be a classmate.
Meeting Regarding Yoshino's Girlfriend
同じ学校の生徒。
広げても　せいぜい→
Even if we were to stretch it, his girlfriend is still likely to be a student at a nearby school.
周辺中高の女子学生
というところではないか？→
Meeting Regarding Yoshino's Girlfriend
そういった女学生との接点は？
Has he had contact with anyone like that?
That trail may be hard to follow.
その線は微妙かもな。　何度か→
I tried to introduce him to girls a few times, but...
彼女を紹介しようとしたことは
あったんだが…。
It's no use.
（愛花）((無駄ですね。
吉野さんの腹黒伝説は→
The legend of Yoshino's maliciousness
この辺りの女子全般に
知れ渡っていますから))
is famous among all the female students in the area.
((伝説って…
あいつは　そんなヤツじゃ…))
Legend? He's not that—
Rumors, at times, can be more severe than the truth.
((うわさは時に
真実より重いんですよ？))
((彼女を
つくってやろうなどとしたら→
If you try to find him a girlfriend, Mahiro,
真広　あなたまで
腐れ外道認定されることでしょう))
even you could be branded a certified "scumbag."
Th-That's harsh.
き…　厳しいんだね　妹さん。
つまり　滝川吉野の彼女は→
So that means Takigawa Yoshino's girlfriend
うわさに惑わされず
その本質を見抜けた娘か。
could see past the rumors, to the truth.
Able to see the truth (important)
Meeting Regarding Yoshino's Girlfriend
（羽村）あの…
なんで　ホワイトボードが？
Um, why is there a whiteboard?
Able to see the truth (important)
書記は必要だろう。
A secretary is vital.
書記って…。
A secretary?
不合理だ。
This is absurd.
（葉風）
≪吉野の彼女は　聞けば聞くほど→
The more I hear about Yoshino's girlfriend, the more it's apparent that she's complicated.
ややこしい娘ときているし→
吉野は　その娘に
べたべたにほれているし→
And Yoshino is head over heels for her.
小憎らしいやら愛しいやら
はっきりせん！≫
I can't tell if it's annoying or endearing!
To think that I, the Princess of Genesis, would be troubled by a love affair,
≪姫宮たる私が色恋に悩み→
それに世の行く末が
かかっているなど…≫
and that it could determine the fate of the world...
≪これは何か!?　ラブコメか!?≫
What is this? A love comedy?
≪世界の命運をかけた
ラブコメなのか!?≫
A love comedy with the fate of the world at stake?!
わあ！　ははっ　おっきいお風呂！
It's such a big bath!
（葉風）だあ～！
えっ!?→
Aaaaagh!
Eeh?
Aaaaah!
きゃあ～～!!
（羽村）う～ん…。　ってかさ
いちばん親しい真広君に→
But doesn't it seem weird that he'd hide his girlfriend from Mahiro, given how close they are?
彼女のこと隠してるって
おかしくないですか？
Then he must have had an important reason to hide her.
（潤一郎）なら　隠しておく
十分な理由があったんだ。→
Maybe she would embarrass him.
知られると恥ずかしい相手とか。
学校の女教師。
A female teacher at his school...
That would be difficult to talk about, even to a close friend.
（左門）ならば
親友にでも話しづらいだろう。
It is also plausible, considering how the public would view it.
世間体もあって隠していた
という理由も考えられる。
あっ　あのさ…。
ならば　人妻はどうだ？
U-Um...
Then how about a married woman?
はあ？
残念ながら→
Unfortunately,
俺と吉野が知ってる人妻ってのは
思いつかねぇ。
I can't think of any married woman that both Yoshino and I would know.
えっと
そういう問題じゃなくて…。
Um, is that really the problem here?
Maybe it's her boobs.
ちちは　どうかな？
ちち？
Boobs?
ちちが　あまりに巨大すぎる女子で
自分の性癖を知られそうで…。
Maybe her boobs were too big,
and his fetish would be discovered...
はっ…　もしくは真逆とか。
（左門）年下という可能性はどうだ。
Or could it be the exact opposite?
A much younger girl, perhaps?
あいつは　年上好きだぞ。
（潤一郎）攪乱させるためかも。
He liked older women.
That could have been misdirection.
（左門）彼女が小学生など
あまりに年下すぎても→
If she were in elementary school, it would've been awkward,
人に話しづらいからな。
given the age difference.
Female Teacher
Married Woman
Boobs
Lolita Complex
これ　書き出す必要あるのかな…。
Was there really any point in writing all this?
（左門）羽村　お前も何かないか？
（羽村）えっ？　えっと→
Hanemura, do you have something to add?
U-Um...
What about the cafeteria lady?
学食のおばさんとか
いいんじゃない？
それはねぇだろ。
（潤一郎）ふざけるのはよくないよ。
No way.
Stop fooling around.
Take this more seriously.
（左門）もっと真剣になれ。
（羽村）君たちに言われたくないよ。
Look who's talking!
I guess it's come down
≪こうなれば　最後の手段を…≫
to my last resort!
マリンスノー…　か。
Marine snow, huh?
((あっ…))
((だから怒っていませんよ))
I told you I'm not angry.
((信じられないけど))
That's hard to believe.
When we're like this, I feel like I could be with you forever.
((こうしていると
いつまでも　吉野さんと→
一緒にいられる気になります))
((愛花ちゃん))
Aika...
((寒いので　いつまでも
こうしていたくはありませんが))
Although it's rather cold,
so I'd prefer not to stay out here forever.
That was one comment too many.
((ひと言　多いよ))
((あっ))
((冷たいね))
It's cold.
((こうして　ずっと一緒に…))
Just like this...
Forever.
Were you contacting your girlfriend?
（葉風）
彼女と連絡を取っていたのか？
あっ…　いえ。
Ah...
No.
ダメだ。
えっ？
I can't...
Huh?
（葉風）このままでは　私は…。
あっ。
At this rate, I...
You'll catch a cold.
風邪ひきますよ。
（葉風）はっ！　やめてくれ！
Stop it!
（葉風）吉野。
はい。
Yoshino...
Yes?
私は　お前が好きだ！
I...
I'm in love with you!
I-I'm sorry?
は…　はい？
好意というレベルではない。
It isn't just that I fancy you...
恋と表現される　最上級の
ドキドキレベルの好きだ！→
It would have to be described
as being so in love with you that my heart won't stop pounding.
今も　お前を抱き締めたいとか→
Even now, I can't stop thinking about my desire to hug you,
耳たぶに触れたいとか
思っておるのだぞ!?
or touch your earlobes!
耳たぶを？
Earlobes?
（葉風）ああ～　もう
じれったいヤツだな！
You're so dense!
I have the protection of the Tree of Genesis.
私には　はじまりの樹の加護が
あるのだぞ？
はじまりの姫宮たる私が→
I am the Princess of Genesis,
お前を我がものにしたいと
欲しているのだ。→
and I desire to make you mine!
お前に
彼女がいるのが腹立たしく→
I can't help but wish that your girlfriend didn't exist.
その娘さえ　この世にいなければと
思ったりするのだ。
最悪の場合→
In the worst case,
the Tree of Genesis will acknowledge that wish.
その私の気持ちを
はじまりの樹が察し→
お前の彼女を　私のために殺し→
It could go as far as killing your girlfriend,
to get rid of her for my sake.
排除しようとするかもしれん。
私は　もはや　自身で
気持ちをコントロールできん！
I can no longer control these feelings!
So, Yoshino, make me give up on you!
だから吉野
私に　お前を諦めさせろ！
ロリの線はねぇよ。
（左門）待て。
There's no chance he's into lolis.
Wait a second.
≪なんだろう≫
What is this?
What about a nurse?
What about a C.A.?
It's like everyone's deliberately avoiding the obvious answer.
≪みんな　わざと
その可能性を外してるのかな≫
A C.A.?
A cabin attendant.
Like, a flight attendant.
（潤一郎）スッチーだよ。
（左門）ありえんな。
Improbable.
（羽村）いいかな？
なんだ？
Could I say something?
What?
（羽村）もし
エア彼女じゃないんだとしたら→
If she's not an imaginary girlfriend...
From everything I've heard,
僕の聞いたかぎり
吉野君の彼女って→
there's only one person that I can
imagine being Yoshino's girlfriend.
一人しか考えられないんだけど。
一人って？
One person?
そうか　このところ
それで様子が変だったんですね。
So that's it.
That's why you've been acting so weird lately.
分かりました。　それなら
もう隠しておかない方がいい。
All right.
Then I probably shouldn't keep this secret anymore.
ん？
彼女のことは　心配いりません。
You don't need to worry about my girlfriend.
どうせ　はじまりの樹にも
どうにもできませんから。
The Tree of Genesis won't be able to do anything to her.
You can't say something that illogical so easily.
そんな　さらっと
理屈に合わんことを言われても→
You can't be sure.
安心できんぞ。
理屈には合ってます。
It's perfectly logical.
「オフィーリアを愛していた。→
I loved Ophelia.
たとえ幾千幾万の兄があり→
Forty thousand brothers
その愛情すべてを
寄せ集めたとしても→
could not, with all their quantity of love,
おれ一人のこの愛には到底」…。
make up my sum.
えっ？
１年前に死んだ彼女の→
Why would you have to worry
何を今更
心配する必要があるんです？
over a girlfriend who died a year ago?
Couldn't Yoshino's girlfriend
吉野君の彼女
真広君の妹さんじゃないかな？
be Mahiro's sister?
（左門）不破…　愛花が？
Fuwa Aika...
kimi no utatta hanauta ga
The song you hummed
boku no hanauta to kasanatta
and the song I hummed were the same
yoku aru koto kamoshirenai kedo
Maybe this is not so rare,
tokubetsu datte omoitainda
but I'd like to believe it's special
tokidoki fuan ni mo naru kara
Sometimes everyone feels anxious
tsui mata sagashite shimaundayo
and we wind up seeking it again
me ni mienai ito no youna
Like an invisible string,
futari wo tsuyoku tsunagi au mono
it is what connects us two
tatoe hoka no dare ga waratte mo
Even if others laugh about that,
boku wa tsuyoku shinjiteru kara
I believe it exists,
ima mo zutto zutto negatte iruyo
and so I keep on wishing even now
futari de iru mirai wo
for a future where we are together
mae wo muite aruite yuku yo
I will look ahead and walk
hitori kiri janai kara
because I am not alone
itsu no hi ka kimi to hora unmei datta ne tte
I hope we can one day laugh and say "Hey, it was destiny"
issho ni waraeru to ii na
Wouldn't that be nice?
Confinement?
（左門）監禁!?
That's right. Hit me, Hanemura.
（葉風）そうだ　私をたたけ　羽村。
The princess... Why?
（夏村）姫様　なぜ…。
Did I say something I shouldn't have?
（羽村）僕　触れちゃいけないとこに
触れちゃいました？
Wh-Wh-Where is this going?
（潤一郎）
こっ　これ　どういう展開!?　えっ!?
Let's consider this...
よく考えさせろ。
I cannot read the future at all.
（左門）まるきり先が読めん。
さっぱり読めん。
Not in the slightest.
Episode 18
The Dancing Princess